[NicFab Blog](https://www.nicfab.eu/en/ "NicFab Blog (Alt + H)")

* |

* [Search](https://www.nicfab.eu/en/search/ "Search (Alt + /)")

[Home](https://www.nicfab.eu/en/) » [Pages](https://www.nicfab.eu/en/pages/)

Privacy Policy
==============

Our Privacy Policy

12 July 2024 · 7 min · NicFab | Translations:

Image by Markus Winkler from Pixabay

Table of Contents

    * [Transferring personal data to a third country or international organisation](#transferring-personal-data-to-a-third-country-or-international-organisation)

Credits: The cover page image is by [Markus Winkler](https://pixabay.com/users/viarami-13458823/?utm_source=link-attribution&utm_medium=referral&utm_campaign=image&utm_content=5243225) from [Pixabay](https://pixabay.com//?utm_source=link-attribution&utm_medium=referral&utm_campaign=image&utm_content=5243225)  
  
**Privacy Policy**

* * *

Matomo _opt-in_ or _opt-out_[#](#matomo-_opt-in_-or-_opt-out_)
==============================================================

1. \[EN\]: **Allow** tracking (or choose 2) - \[IT\]: **Consento** al tracking (o scegli 2)

2. \[EN\]: **Disallow** tracking - \[IT\]: **Non consento** al tracking

**Opt-in:** **\[EN\]** You **allowed** tracking - **\[IT\]** **Hai consentito** al tracking

**Opt-out:** **\[EN\]** You are **not** tracked - **\[IT\]** I dati di sessione **non** sono raccolti.

If you have chosen “Allow tracking” we remind you that we will collect your data only in an anonymous and aggregated manner as [reported in this policy](https://www.nicfab.eu/en/pages/privacy-policy/#matomo).  
You can still change your choices at any time.

* * *

Privacy Policy[#](#privacy-policy)
==================================

We provide this information according to the [EU Regulation 2016/679 (GDPR)](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&from=EN) for those who consult the website [https://www.nicfab.eu](https://www.nicfab.eu/) and [https://notes.nicfab.eu](https://notes.nicfab.eu/). Note that this information applies only to those NicFab website and not to other websites that the user may consult through links.

Data controller[#](#data-controller)
------------------------------------

The data controller is Nicola Fabiano (info \[at\] nicfab.eu).

Legal basis for the processing[#](#legal-basis-for-the-processing)
------------------------------------------------------------------

The purpose is to consult this website, and the processing of personal data is based on consent - according to article 6, par. 1, lett. a) of EU Regulation 2016/679 - expressed by the user by browsing this website and its consultation, thus accepting this information. Consent is optional, and the user can withdraw at any time by request sent by email to privacy \[at\] nicfab.eu, specifying that, in this case, whether the user does not consent, they cannot consult this website, and the navigation might be compromised.

The processing of personal data is necessary to pursue the legitimate interest of the data controller to provide information about studies and research, according to art. 6, par. 1, letter f) of EU Regulation 2016/679, in compliance with the provisions of the same Regulation.

Processing of data[#](#processing-of-data)
------------------------------------------

### _Browsing data_[#](#_browsing-data_)

The user (data subject) can access this website and navigate through a web browser. Some data are necessary for surfing the Internet and could identify users through processing and association with data held by third parties. In particular, we intend to refer to the IP addresses or domain names of the computers used by users connecting to this website, the addresses in URI (Uniform Resource Identifier) notation of the requested resources, the time of the request, etc. We could use these data uniquely for anonymous statistical information on the use of the website and check its correct functioning and are deleted immediately after processing. We could use data for any responsibility in the hypothesis of computer crimes connected to this website. Data relating to those who have submitted requests to NicFab using the tools on this website are stored for no more than seven days, however, for the time necessary to provide the answers and for any need to ascertain part of the judicial authority.

### _Data communicated by users_[#](#_data-communicated-by-users_)

The optional, explicit, and voluntary sending of electronic mail to the addresses indicated on this site involves the acquisition of the sender’s address necessary for the replies and any other personal data contained in the message. These data are processed to respond to messages sent and handle any related requests. Failure to provide personal data for communications with NicFab or send any requests will prevent evading them. We store data for the time strictly necessary for the purposes related to data processing.

Cookies[#](#cookies)
--------------------

Cookies (small text files that the visited website sends to your device, where they are then stored to be re-transmitted to the same website at the next visit) can be _permanent_ or _session_, “_First-party_” (site or domain of origin), or “_Third-party_” (from third parties). Persistent cookies consist of a text file sent from a web server to a web browser. Once stored by the browser, it remains valid until the scheduled expiration date (unless the visitor deletes it before the time mentioned above). Session cookies expire at the end of the session or when the user closes the web browser. “_First-party_” cookies are those set by this site; “_Third-party_” cookies are of a different domain than this one, and they are set up because they use functions managed by third parties. Our website uses the following cookies:

_Session cookies_ (which are not stored permanently on the user’s computer and disappear when the browser is closed) and are strictly limited to the transmission of session identifiers (consisting of random numbers generated by the server) necessary to allow safe browsing and efficiency of the site. Session cookies used on this site avoid using other technologies that could compromise the privacy of users’ browsing and do not allow the acquisition of personal data.

It is, however, possible for the user to set cookies from the “Preferences” of the browser used and eventually automatically refuse the receipt of cookies by activating the appropriate option: the non-use of technical cookies, however, could involve technical difficulties of interaction with this website.

You can find instructions for disabling cookies on the following web pages:

In the case of sharing the content of this website on other platforms, the collection and use of information by third parties unrelated to this site are governed by their privacy policies to which we invite you to refer; we report references to the leading social platforms:

* [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/) (cookie policy)
* [Twitter](https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en) (cookie policy)
* [LinkedIn](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy) (cookie policy)

### Matomo[#](#matomo)

This site uses **only session cookies** [**Matomo**](https://matomo.org/) for Web Analytics to acquire _statistics in an anonymous and aggregate form_ related to your navigation on the pages of this site.

We have set the -do not track support- leaving the choice to the user to disable the opt-out.

The user can activate opt-in or deactivate opt-out anytime from the home page or at the top of this page.

**Thus, this site does not use cookies other than session cookies solely for the functional purposes described above, and their installation does not require the user’s consent**.

Data recipients[#](#data-recipients)
------------------------------------

We do not communicate personal data collected from this website following its consultation to recipients or categories of recipients.

Period for storing personal data[#](#period-for-storing-personal-data)
----------------------------------------------------------------------

Apart from what is specified above, the data collected by this website during its operation are stored for the time strictly necessary for the activities specified. The data will be deleted or anonymised at the expiry date unless there are no further purposes for storing the same. For analytics purposes (statistics), we use Matomo but on the condition that you have agreed to this by providing consent once you have reached this site. Data for analytics purposes is stored in aggregate form for 30 days.

Transferring personal data to a third country or international organisation[#](#transferring-personal-data-to-a-third-country-or-international-organisation)
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

This website does not share data with services located outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

Security measures[#](#security-measures)
----------------------------------------

Visitors’ or users’ data are processed lawfully and correctly by adopting appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of data. Your data in the communication session with this website are protected by a Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) certificate that uses a cryptographic presentation protocol, encrypting the information. In addition to the controller, in some cases, authorized persons may have access to the data as involved in the organization of the website or external subjects (such as third-party technical service providers, hosting providers).

Data subjects’ rights[#](#data-subjects-rights)
-----------------------------------------------

Users (data subject) of this website may exercise the rights according to Articles 15 to 22 of EU Regulation 2016/679. You can lodge all requests to exercise these rights by writing to privacy \[at\] nicfab.eu.

Right to lodge a complaint[#](#right-to-lodge-a-complaint)
----------------------------------------------------------

Whether a data subject considers that the processing of personal data relating to him or her as performed via this website infringes the Regulation, he or she has the right to lodge a complaint with the Garante according to Article 77 of the EU Regulation 2016/679.

© 2024 [NicFab Blog](https://www.nicfab.eu/en/) Powered by [Hugo](https://gohugo.io/) & [PaperMod](https://github.com/adityatelange/hugo-PaperMod/)

[](#top "Go to Top (Alt + G)")
